[The Heir]
[Episode 12]
Look at the lines of
the Four-season painting.
You can touch it.
Touch it?
May I?
Yes.
Zhengliang, touch it.
Third Aunt is skillful, right?
Let me see.
Manager Shao seems like a rough man,
but his gold-tracing technique is amazing.
There are exactly four pieces.
The Spring piece
is for my beautiful sister-in-law.
Thank you, Zhen.
The Summer piece
is for my loud-voiced mother.
Thank you, Zhen.
The Autumn piece is for my honest brother.
As for the Winter piece,
it conceals its sharpness
to store its energy.
That is for Grandfather.
Grandfather,
the Li family's ink workshop
is incredible,
much tidier than others.
When I was young,
I used to play hide-and-seek inside,
going in and out,
but I never knew what that place was for.
Going back this time,
I finally got the hang of it.
I couldn't even count
the amazing things in the ink workshop.
If I could spend
months with the workers in it,
I'd develop many new inks.
Zhen.
Although you intended to go back,
I'm afraid the Li family
won't accept you.
Zhen.
Tell me,
what are
your plans?
I'll make a plan
after the ink testing event ends.
The lacquer-soot ink isn't truly finished
until the ink testing event is over.
Zhen.
After the event,
the lacquer-soot ink
has nothing to do with you.
It doesn't matter, Mother.
Anyway, I have all these skills.
If I win a prize,
I'll buy us a new house.
Grandfather,
will you go to the event?
The colleagues of the Huizhou ink industry
will definitely all be there.
Since I have long sworn
to quit the ink industry,
it wouldn't be appropriate for me to go.
However,
I wish
that your lacquer-soot ink,
the Li family's lacquer-soot ink,
will be a great success.
Okay.
I, a maker of lacquer-soot ink, Li Zhen,
announce that
my first ink testing event
starts now.
What do you think?
Let me take a look.
The ink on the lines is like lacquer.
It gives off a lively shine
where the stroke ends.
As for the layers, it's lyrical
and dynamic.
Good ink.
It's a top-notch ink.
Grandfather.
Did I look like you?
[Li's Residence]
[Cuiqiao Cottage]
[The Mortuary Tablet of
Late Husband Yu Gonghai]
Sister.
I didn't expect Miss Li Zhen
could restore
the ancient lacquer-soot ink.
Li Zhen has a talent for ink making.
But I didn't expect
that the one who got involved
would be her.
Things have settled down.
Since you've tested the waters,
the way forward is clear now, right?
It's my good fortune
that God grants my wishes.
It seems you have made up your mind
to invest in Li Ink.
I wonder
whether your decision
involves any selfish motives.
Sister.
The hardest thing in the world
is to have it both ways.
Since there is an opportunity now,
why don't I seize it?
Right, Sister?
I was a merchant on the sea.
You are a fugitive on the run.
We are both outcasts.
If Marshal Qi
and General didn't take us in,
we would have died long ago.
Marshal Qi and General have done us
a tremendous favor.
But Sister,
what exactly do you want to say?
I know about your blood feud
with the Tian family.
But preparing military supplies
is the top priority
of our trip to Huizhou.
We have been sworn siblings for years,
no different from biological ones.
As your sister,
I can't watch you act on impulse,
mess up the task,
and bring trouble upon yourself.
You're right.
Thank you for the reminder.
I will definitely go all out
and handle the military supplies properly.
But
how can I stop
avenging them for my family?
I just hope
you don't act impulsively.
[Qingfeng Pavilion]
I know what to do.
Sister.
Don't worry.
Girl.
The invitations for people in Jinling
have already been sent out.
As for the major ink merchants
and managers in Huizhou,
I will let
someone deliver them later.
I will go personally to the ink workshops
that have good relations with Li Ink,
and to Third Master Chen.
But as for Lord Yan,
you should go invite him yourself
as you are the maker of
the ancient lacquer-soot ink.
Good idea.
Sixth Grandfather, I will go now.
Go ahead.
[Deshan Hall]
Are you going to the ink workshop again?
I changed the ink recipe today.
I seem to have some clues.
Then, go quickly!
The deadline is approaching.
We can't let the whole Huizhou
laugh at Tian Ink.
I'm afraid we are bound to become a joke.
Li Zhen
managed to recreate
the ancient lacquer-soot ink!
I heard that
the Li family is going
to hold an ink testing event.
They invited all major merchants
and famous scholars in Huizhou
to test the ink in their shop.
Father, what should we do?
Why panic?
The Li family wants
to hold an ink testing event?
Okay.
I'd like to see
how they're going to pull off
the ink testing event.
[Yan's Mansion]
[To Lord Yan]
I remember that
your family also announced
to restore the ancient lacquer-soot ink.
Yes.
But now,
the Li family has already made it.
Why is your family holding
another ink testing event?
What are you
going to do?
Lord Yan.
I didn't want to be so ostentatious.
But my father asked someone
to send this Baibao Ink
to the capital
and present it to Lord Xu.
Lord Xu praised it after using it.
I want to hold an event
to honor Lord Xu's favor.
Lord Yan, I hope you will grace
us with your presence
and join this grand event.
You...
Master,
Miss Li Zhen is here to deliver
the invitation for
the lacquer-soot ink testing event.
Invite her in.
Okay.
What a coincidence.
You just delivered an innovation,
and Miss Li Zhen followed it instantly.
What a coincidence!
What a coincidence.
Coincidence indeed.
Zhen.
I didn't expect such a coincidence.
Our two families' ink testing events
are on the exact same day.
Our ink
has already been recognized
by Lord Xu in the capital.
I'm afraid Lord Yan
won't be able to attend your event.
I really didn't expect
you to have such a trick.
Don't blame me.
I'm not targeting you.
There are no friends in business,
only winners and losers.
But it's still too early to say
who'll come out on top.
Goodbye.
The Tian family
chose to hold their ink testing event
on the same day as ours.
Their intention is self-evident.
Shameless.
Despicable.
Rujun.
Shall we change the date of
our ink testing event?
Zhen.
What do you think?
Seventh Grandmother.
If we blindly make a change
because of external affairs,
we will lose our own direction.
I don't think we can change the date.
Well...
Doing so carries significant risks.
Now,
compared to the Tian Ink,
the odds of our winning are not great.
Then, we must find a way
to increase our odds.
You have an idea?
Seventh Grandmother,
if we could have
an influential master
of calligraphy and painting
to test Li Ink,
and an influential
ink merchant present
to help sell the lacquer-soot ink,
our ink testing event will be a success,
right?
Yes.
Thank about
the candidates for the ink tester.
Do you have any suggestions?
Mother,
there are a few calligraphy masters
on good terms with the Li family.
Mr. Guangyuan is good at seal script.
Mr. Yuanyou is a Court Style.
Mother,
who do you prefer?
Eldest Aunt.
I think neither of these two gentlemen
is suitable for testing
the lacquer-soot ink.
Why?
As for our pine soot ink,
it has a vigorous color.
The seal script matches the Court Style.
But the lacquer-soot ink
excels in variation.
Fluctuating lines
can fully reflect its characteristics.
For testing ink in calligraphy
and painting,
landscape painting is the best.
Seventh Grandmother,
what do you think of Mr. Dongtu?
Who?
Zhan Dongtu?
Are you sleepwalking?
Li Zhen,
do you know Mr. Dongtu?
Do you know his temper?
You're talking nonsense.
Zhan Dongtu...
Rujun.
Mr. Dongtu
only associates with Third Master Chen
and only tests ink for the Chen family.
I'm afraid we will fail to invite him.
Sixth Grandfather,
if we don't try,
how do we know it won't work?
Zhen is right.
Since you already have a plan in mind,
I will leave
this ink testing event entirely to you.
Master.
There's no problem with this account.
Okay.
Master Qi.
What a coincidence.
Miss Li Zhen,
why do you have the leisure to
visit my humble abode?
No one comes knocking without a reason.
I'm here for you.
Now that I'm here,
won't you invite me in for a cup of tea?
Since you need my favour,
I naturally have good tea to treat you.
Please come in.
Thank you.
Mr. He, make tea.
Okay, Master.
Miss Li Zhen, please take a seat.
That is a couch.
Have a seat.
Miss Li Zhen,
what do you want to do?
I came especially to thank you, Master Qi.
For what?
Thank you for
finding the bile for me.
Just for this?
Just for this.
You're welcome.
Master, the tea is here.
Good.
Thank you.
Please.
You drink it too.
Good tea.
Miss Li Zhen,
even without me,
you would definitely
find the answer.
Miss Li Zhen,
what exactly is your business
with me today?
Master Qi, you're so smart.
I came today
for some other matters.
Please say it.
Tian and Li are holding ink testing events
on the same day.
Li Ink needs a major ink merchant
to hold the fort.
So, I want to...
The Tian family?
Did they
restore the ancient lacquer-soot ink?
Of course not.
They just want to embarrass Li Ink
and ruin our ink testing event.
If our ink testing event fails,
not only will Lord Yan lose face,
but your long-standing plans
will also be in vain.
But
it's hard for me
to invite
a major ink merchant.
You flatter me.
The whole Huizhou knows
Master Qi's capability.
If you find it difficult,
just pretend that I never came today.
No rush.
Please.
Thank you.
Then, Master Qi,
I won't disturb you anymore.
I'll take my leave now.
Take care.
Bye.
Miss Li Zhen.
Please rest assured, Miss Li Zhen.
I've known about this issue.
I will do my best to help you.
Thank you, Master Qi.
Girl,
you are truly amazing.
Thank you, Third Grandfather.
Rest assured.
I will definitely attend
your ink testing event to support you.
Thank you, Third Grandfather.
I came today to ask you
to recommend someone
to paint for the event.
I can't.
Third Grandfather,
I haven't even said who it is yet.
Since you came to me,
who else could it be but Mr. Dongtu?
Third Grandfather.
Chen Ink has cooperated with
Mr. Dongtu for years.
You must be very close.
Please help me.
Girl,
I'd like to help you,
but I can't.
For the past year, Mr. Dongtu has
devoted himself to painting
the Xin'an River Landscape painting.
He has tried and failed many times.
So,
he went to Mount Qiyun
to paint in seclusion.
Okay.
Since you won't help me,
then I will go invite him myself.
I came here today
to let you know,
so as not to lose my manners.
Third Grandfather, I'm leaving.
Wait.
Mount Qiyun is so big.
You haven't traveled much.
Where will you find him?
How about this?
Discuss this issue with your family, okay?
No need.
I don't know where to find him either.
I'll just go to Mount Qiyun
and walk around
to look for him.
I'll walk for three or four days,
look around,
and see where Mr. Dongtu is.
Anyway, I'm not
your biological granddaughter,
and you don't care about me at all.
Just let me look for him alone.
Stop!
Take this with you.
Mr. Dongtu will see you.
Thank you, Third Grandfather.
Then, I will take my leave.
I haven't finished yet.
Go ahead.
Mr. Dongtu is a master
of calligraphy and painting.
Don't be abrupt.
Whether this works or not
depends on
you.
I understand.
I know
you adore me the most.
Bye.
Miss Li Zhen.
Why are you here?
Are you going to Mount Qiyun
to look for Mr. Dongtu?
You're quite well-informed.
If you don't mind,
would you like to go with me?
Mount Qiyun
is high and far.
There might be inconveniences
for you to go alone.
If we go together, we can take care of
each other on the road.
What do you think?
Let's go.
Daddy.
Run faster.
Daddy, I'm tired.
I want a piggyback ride.
Daddy, a little faster.
Come on, hold on tight.
What's up?
Nothing.
I just thought of my dad.
When I was young,
my dad would carry me like this
and walk through this archway.
I've heard of your father,
the son of Eighth Master Li, the head
of the Five Ink-making Grandmasters.
The title of the rising star
of Hui Ink is well deserved.
What a pity.
My father passed away too early.
Then,
we are in the same boat.
My father passed away early too.
Tell me,
did your father
like to challenge things
that seemed impossible, just like you?
Was your father
as helpful as you are?
♪ Raindrops fall on
the moss-covered stone steps ♪
[Mount Qiyun]
Let's go.
Go
♪ With a bamboo knife,
you make the spring fade away ♪
♪ Last year's branches are still
hanging in the window ♪
♪ The tea left a stain on the sleeve ♪
I'm exhausted.
♪ The wreathing smoke
gradually dissipated ♪
Let's sit here and take a rest.
♪ Counting the games of our childhood ♪
♪ You lower your eyes
and count the rings of the tree ♪
Let's rest here for a bit.
♪ Scars meander like a stream ♪
♪ The ink-black distant mountains
resemble your eyes and brows ♪
♪ Amid the inky darkness,
it seems as though a galaxy is shifting ♪
When you were in front just now,
did you cut your hand?
It's nothing. Look.
♪ Lend me a bit of
the courage of a piece of pine resin ♪
I wish there were rouge ink.
♪ Amid the frost,
I sketch the unfinished prologue ♪
What ink?
Rouge ink.
♪ The hazy, distant mountains
are just like you ♪
It's a kind of medicinal ink.
Applying it to the wound
can reduce swelling and stop bleeding.
♪ A winding bridge
reflected in the water pavilion ♪
But the rouge ink
is rare even in Huizhou.
♪ If we are to part ways ♪
When I was little and playful,
every time I went out,
♪ Let the ink speak for me and say,
“Take care” ♪
I would come back with injuries.
My father
specially developed it for me.
But the last piece of rouge ink
was given away.
To whom?
A little boy.
It was on the Mid-Autumn Festival
when I met that little boy.
At that time,
he was being bullied by someone.
I went up to help him.
Then, he followed me
to enjoy Harvest Eve Foraging
and got injured.
Then, I took him back to my house,
used rouge ink to treat his wounds,
and gave it to him.
A little boy
was bullied,
and you saved him?
He's a coward.
But was it proper
to bring a boy
you just met home?
What are you talking about?
He was so little.
He wouldn't hurt me.
Besides,
at that time,
I already considered him my friend.
Friend?
Friend.
You don't know how cute he was.
When I met him,
he was a head shorter than me.
His whole face was round,
and his eyes were round, too.
He also had two small hair buns.
He was incredibly cute.
If you saw him,
you would definitely like him too.
Maybe.
But soon his father took him home.
Later,
something happened to his family,
and I never saw him again.
I wonder where he is
and how he's doing now.
Maybe
he's already gone.
Since he is your friend,
then I wish him well.
But having a friend like you
to remember him,
he'd be very comforted
if he were alive.
We've been walking for a while.
You must be hungry.
Here you are.
Stone Guozi.
Filling our stomachs
will also keep us warm.
You're not from here.
How did you know we locals will
take Stone Guozi
as dry rations when traveling?
I'm just following the local customs.
Actually, my father used
to do business in Huizhou
and loved Huizhou food so much
that our chef at home
was hired from Huizhou.
The chef often made Stone Guozi,
so he also frequently told me
about the customs of Stone Guozi.
You really are a young master
from a wealthy family.
You even specially hired
a chef from Huizhou.
What about the rest of your family?
Are they still in your hometown now?
It's not peaceful there.
Our home was attacked by bandits.
Except for me,
all my family members were
killed by bandits.
I was the only one who luckily escaped.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know your past
was so rough.
That's all in the past.
But
in the past, I really was
a young master of a wealthy family.
But now,
I can only rely on my own
to build a business.
That is a really capable man.
It's getting late.
Let's keep moving.
It's cold in the mountains too.
Okay.
Let's go.
Please come in, you two.
Mr. Dongtu,
I am Li Zhen.
I came here specifically to invite you
to test the new ancient lacquer-soot ink
of the Li family.
[Mr. Dongtu]
Third Master Chen
rarely speaks up so easily.
It seems he really likes you two.
The spring cold in Mount Qiyun
hasn't passed lately.
I just brewed a pot of tea.
Have some
to ward off the cold.
Thank you, Mr. Dongtu.
You came all this way.
The way must have been
hard to travel, right?
Although it was difficult,
there was a sea of clouds
and strange pines along the way
with clear mountains and waters.
It felt like walking into a painting.
Mount Qiyun is indeed a blessed
and sacred Taoist mountain.
Master Qi.
I built this studio here.
Do you know why?
Then, I will make a bold guess.
I just observed that
all of your paintings,
whether it's mountain views
or river views,
feature pine trees.
Could it be related
to the pine scenery here?
That's right.
All my life,
I have loved nothing but pine trees.
But nowadays, the pine forests in Huizhou
are getting sparser year by year.
Only by retreating here
can I find this ideal place.
The pine forests are sparse
because of the booming
ink industry in Huizhou, right?
Mr. Dongtu,
my grandfather said
that thousand-year-old pine wood
was everywhere before.
But now, if ink makers want to
find century-old pine wood,
they have to go deep into the mountains.
Green and straight pine trees
were cut down,
made into an inkstick,
and then handed to me
to paint the disappearing pine scenery.
It's really ridiculous
and tragic.
Pine trees are the soul of Huizhou
and the foundation of the ink industry.
If no one plants pine trees,
future generations will have
no pines to use or admire.
Mr. Dongtu,
I promise you, substituting tea for wine,
that I will plant pine trees
every year from now on
for Huizhou,
for the ink industry,
for you, Mr. Dongtu,
and also for future generations.
Then,
count me in.
I will follow Miss Li Zhen
to do something for the ink industry
and pine forests
in Huizhou.
Good.
Since you are so sincere,
when I go down the mountain
depends on you two.
We are back.
Where are you going, Miss Li Zhen?
I...
I'm going home.
I didn't expect you
to be somewhat useful.
Thank you for this time.
I'll go back first.
Okay.
Your bag.
I'm leaving.
Goodbye.
Does it hurt?
No.
Not at all.
At that time,
I already considered him my friend.
Friend?
I wonder where he is
and how he's doing now.
Maybe
he's already gone.
[Li Ink]
In the past days,
everyone was eager to restore
the lacquer-soot ink.
Raw lacquer on the market
was already very scarce,
and the Tian family aggressively bought up
all the available stock
within a hundred miles.
Sixth Master
only has this left.
How much lacquer-soot ink
can this raw lacquer produce?
Even at maximum capacity,
we can only produce ten catties.
That is far from enough.
Listen,
send all our people
out to find raw lacquer.
You can assign the servants at will.
Go north to Xi'an,
and south to Zhangzhou.
Hurry.
Yes.
[Ink Workshop]
Manager Shao,
Seven or eight carriages are outside,
carrying
five hundred catties of raw lacquer.
Who sent them?
The leader's name is Xiao Qi.
He said
Master Qi from Yihousheng
sent it especially to our family.
Master Qi.
Your raw lacquer
is truly a timely help
for Li Ink.
It solves our urgent need.
I
will use tea instead of wine
to toast you.
Seventh Old Madam, don't be so polite.
Even without my raw lacquer,
I think this small matter wouldn't
stump you,
as you have been powerful
in the ink industry for many years.
It's just that
I
have traveled far and wide for many years,
and have seen more
petty tricks of despicable people
than you,
so I stayed ahead of them
by taking one more step.
You are too modest, Master Qi.
The ink testing event is tomorrow.
Zhen has invited Mr. Dongtu.
Your raw lacquer
is precious
to the Li family.
Master Qi,
the Li family's business
has always valued fairness.
No matter what the price of raw lacquer
in Huizhou is,
I will definitely pay
every penny to you.
Old Madam,
I am a businessman.
So, I don't care about
immediate petty profits.
The reason I came this time
is to establish
a long-term business
with the Li family.
Not only will I give this raw lacquer
to Li Ink for free,
but I will also take out
one thousand taels of silver
to invest in the ancient lacquer-soot ink.
It seems
your intention
to give us the raw lacquer
is not to help us.
Old Madam, you worry too much.
The raw lacquer is
my sincerity in cooperating
with the Li family.
We invited Mr. Dongtu
to the ink testing event,
but those ink merchants and scholars
haven't replied to the invitation yet.
The ancient lacquer-soot ink may
not be a great success.
How could I
let you
bear such a risk?
Old Madam,
business
is bound to have risks.
Thank you for considering
my interests, Old Madam.
But I am a businessman,
so I never fear risks,
and I'm willing
to bear the consequences voluntarily.
The Li family and Li Ink
are my only choice for cooperation.
Thank you,
Master Qi, for your high
regard for Li Ink.
But
investing in ancient lacquer-soot ink
is about passing down
the heritage of Li Ink.
It's not just a simple business deal.
Seventh Old Madam,
I see.
After the ink testing event ends,
I
will visit you again.